The last time I saw Sengoku Nadeko was more than six years ago.
So when we met again, I couldn't recognize her at first.
Had I noticed it was her a lot sooner,
perhaps this story wouldn't have concluded in such a terrible manner.
But that regret
certainly has no meaning for the spirit either.
Was that girl...
I didn't think I'd find a person this deep in the mountains.
And she was pretty damn cute.
Let's just keep going.
Also, watch your feet.
Bug bites are unavoidable, but a lot of snakes come out in this mountain.
Okay.
By the way, Araragi-senpai.
I forgot to ask you yesterday, but what are we doing on this mountain?
A job.
From Oshino.
Apparently, there's an abandoned shrine at the top of the mountain,
and he wants us to place a seal there.
Couldn't Oshino-san have done that himself?
He doesn't look very busy.
Well... it's work.
I owe him a ridiculous amount of debt from when he took care of me.
You do, too, Kanbaru.
He is still a professional.
He's not nice enough to lend us a hand for free.
Oh, so that's why.
By the way, Araragi-senpai.
Did Senjougahara-senpai say anything about today?
Not in particular, no.
Kanbaru, did she say something to you?
She told me to be spoiled as much as possible.
She also told me...
"If Araragi-kun violates you, report to me immediately.
Whether it's to be buried in the mountains or drowned in the sea, I'll let him choose the one he doesn't like."
Choose the one I don't like?!
Oh yeah, Kanbaru.
I just remembered about Senjougahara.
It's her birthday soon, right?
Yeah.
July 7th.
So I was thinking about celebrating her birthday,
and I want to make my first time celebrating it really spectacular,
inviting all her friends for a nice birthday party, you know?
Well...
I think Senjougahara-senpai will want to spend the day alone with you.
I don't think she's that type of a woman.
Hey, Kanbaru.
Yes, Araragi-senpai?
Your... left hand.
How's it doing?
According to Oshino-san, it'll be better before I turn twenty.
That's great to hear.
You'll be able to play basketball again once you're twenty.
Yeah.
What's wrong, Kanbaru?
I'm a little tired...
Tired?
Then do you want to rest somewhere?
Where can we sit...
Actually, Araragi-senpai, how about we have lunch?
Lunch?
Yeah.
When I'm sick, I usually feel better after filling up my stomach.
All right.
Then Kanbaru, could you look for an open spot where we can eat?
I'll go place this seal in the meantime.
Sure.
I'm really sorry, but I'll have to ask you to finish the job, Araragi-senpai.
Okay.
It feels like I've seen her somewhere before.
But,
I hardly get the chance to meet girls in junior high unless it's through my sisters...
Sisters?
Oh, is this the main shrine?
There, all done.
Hey, Kanbaru!
Kanbaru!
Kanbaru?!
Kanbaru.
Oh, it's you, Araragi-senpai.
Hey, what do you mean, "Oh, it's you?"
Oh, sorry.
My heart just jumped.
You don't look good.
Are you okay?
If you're feeling really sick,
I think you can lay down at the porch of the shrine after I move some stuff around.
No.
Araragi-senpai.
That's not it.
Look... at that.
Was her name...
Sengoku Nadeko?
This, and I think this.
Oh, that book might not help you much.
If you want to go to a public college, I think this book's more helpful.
I have to say...
I'm a little surprised that you asked me to find you some reference books for college.
Yeah...
I thought I'd start thinking about my future.
Your future?
Senjougahara and I were talking about it sometime ago,
and I asked her about what school she was applying for, but...
If I remember correctly, Senjougahara-san's been invited to attend the public college in town, right?
You sure know everything.
It's not that I know everything. I just know what I know.
So Araragi-kun...
Are you saying you're applying for the same school as Senjougahara-san?
Don't tell her about this.
I don't want to give her any false hope.
By the way, Araragi-kun.
Yeah, what do you need?
You know how you told me at school that you went to an abandoned shrine yesterday?
I have a question about that.
What did you do after you found a snake in five parts?
Oh, that?
Nothing, really.
Kanbaru and I dug a grave for the snake.
But when we looked around after that, we found a mountain of dead snakes.
A mountain?
Yeah. A mountain of chopped up snakes.
Then we immediately descended the mountain,
and had lunch that Kanbaru packed at a nearby park.
I see.
And I was really amazed at how good it tasted.
Apparently, her grandma helped her.
Well, sounds like you had a tough time, Araragi-kun.
Yeah.
It felt like some ritual to see snakes being killed in that way, so it made me think.
Especially since it was near that rundown shrine.
Oh, Hanekawa.
Did you already know there was a shrine there?
Yeah. The Kitashira Snake Shrine, right?
Snake, huh?
I guess...
Perhaps they worshiped snakes.
I don't know much about it either, so...
Butchered snakes at a shrine that worshiped them...
Sounds like a ritual.
I guess I should tell Oshino...
about this.
Araragi-kun, when I said you had a tough time, I was talking about you and Kanbaru-san.
About you and Kanbaru-san.
That's what I was referring to.
About Kanbaru?
Oh, I guess.
She suddenly fell ill, so I got kind of scared,
but I'm glad it turned out to be nothing.
That's not what I meant.
Isn't it a problem to get too close with your girlfriend's junior?
It's not a problem to be a little friendly, but I don't think linking arms is acceptable.
Don't look at me.
She's a generally clingy person.
You think that's an acceptable excuse?
Well...
But...
I already received a warning from Senjougahara.
I will not tolerate any rudeness towards my junior.
Or something like that.
And she apparently told Kanbaru to ask me to take care of her.
I see.
Would this be what she means?
Here you go.
Like that?
Did you need another second, Araragi-kun?
What do you mean?
Araragi-kun, you're weak and pale.
You know how you're kind to just about anyone?
I think from Senjougahara-san's point of view, that isn't very reassuring.
Isn't reassuring?
I don't think Senjougahara-san actually wants you to be very close with Kanbaru-san.
No.
You can be close, or rather she wants you two to be close,
but she wants you to be firm about it.
I think she wants you to choose her in comparison to Kanbaru-san.
What the hell...
I don't get it.
It's probably Senjougahara-san's dilemma.
You're her valuable boyfriend, and Kanbaru-san's an important junior to her.
Well... since Senjougahara-san's a tsundere,
I don't think it's right to take her actions for what they are.
You have to read deep into them.
You too, Araragi-kun.
If you truly find Senjougahara-san important,
I don't think you should sway from an insignificant temptation.
It's irresponsible to be nice to everyone.
Yeah, I know now, thanks to you.
By the way, where are you applying, Hanekawa?
Tokyo University?
Or are you going to study abroad?
Oh?
I'm not going to college.
Wait, you're not?
Nope.
I'm going on a journey once I graduate.
A journey?
I thought I'd spend two years or so seeing the world.
Since I seem to be too focused on pursuing knowledge,
I figured I should gain a lot of other experiences.
Keep this a secret from the teachers.
They'd probably jump if they found out.
I doubt that's all they'd do.
Ouch.
What's wrong?
Oh, just a little headache.
A headache?
It's nothing.
It recently started to happen from time to time.
It starts hurting without a warning.
Hey, that doesn't sound like nothing.
Do you want me to walk you home?
No thanks.
My home's...
Oh, yeah...
Sorry about that.
It's okay.
But... I'm sorry.
I'll be going now.
Oh, sure. See ya.
Bye.
Sengoku?
This book's...
Kanbaru?
I want to ask you for a little help.
So what did you need me for?
Do you remember the girl we met when we were going up these stairs yesterday?
Yeah.
She was a cute small girl.
I thought I had seen her somewhere, and it hit me when I just saw her at the bookstore.
She's my younger sister's old friend.
Really?
And is that girl here again?
That's right.
I think.
And I asked for your help because...
Well... though she's an old friend, I don't know how to approach her.
She probably doesn't remember me, so it could look like I'm flirting with her,
and a girl who just started puberty can have pretty scary reactions.
I see that you have some experience.
Well, I can't deny that.
On the other hand, Kanbaru, you look like you know how to handle younger girls.
Considering that you're the number one star in school.
I see.
I understand what you're trying to say.
Indeed, I am good at dealing with younger girls.
I figured.
I'm glad I asked you.
Since it's your request, I'm not at all reluctant about helping you,
but this matter also has to do with what we saw yesterday, right?
Well, yeah.
So... that's how it is?
Yeah.
Oh, man.
Sengoku!
Stop, Sengoku!
Koyomi-oniichan?
Friend.
I'm Sengoku Nadeko, second grade, class one.
I don't have very many friends.
But Rara-chan plays with me.
When Rara-chan invites me to play, my heart feels lifted.
Also, Rara-chan has a brother in sixth grade.
His name is Koyomi, and...
Well, come in.
You changed your room.
Yeah.
I got my own room now.
My sisters are still in their old room.
They'll probably be back in a while, so do you want to see them?
So this is Araragi-senpai's room!
It's my first time in a guy's room.
Now then, time to look for some porn magazines.
That... is an event that only occurs when a guy comes to play in another guy's room!
Just be quiet and sit right there!
However, I believe knowing your taste won't be completely meaningless to me.
To me, it'll be more than problematic.
Right, so problematic materials...
You're the personification of a problematic material!
You can sit right there or jump out the window!
No other choice, Kanbaru!
I've already uncovered your taste when I stalked you in the past.
I know the title of every pornography magazine you bought in the recent past.
What?!
That's impossible!
No one was in that store when I bought it!
I made sure of that.
You have quite the maniacal taste.
You only have one choice!
Jump out the window!
If you asked for such play, any ordinary girl would try to run away even if she has to jump out the window.
But not to worry.
It's hardly a challenge for a girl of my caliber.
She's proud about it!
Koyomi-oniichan...
and Kanbaru-san,
may I request that you turn around for a bit?
I'm done now.
Please turn around.
Bloomers?
Oh, Araragi-senpai.
I lent her the bloomers that I coincidentally had.
I see.
Junior Kanbaru.
You carry around bloomers by pure chance?
It's what any lady would do.
No, that would apply to perverts.
I can understand that Sengoku doesn't want to show us her underwear,
but bloomers...
What's that?
Looks like rope marks from bondage play.
Are those... scales? From fish?
No, in her case, it would be a reptile? Snakes?
Koyomi-oniichan.
Since you're an adult, you won't feel lustful from seeing my body, right?
Oh, yeah.
Of course I won't.
Right, Kanbaru?
Well, I don't know, Araragi-senpai.
I would think that stating you have absolutely no interest in a lady in the nude
is in fact more of an insult to a girl.
I see.
I'll correct myself.
I do have some dirty thoughts from seeing your body.
Hey, Kanbaru!
I did as you said, and I made a junior high girl cry!
I didn't think you'd tell her so directly.
Hey, Sengoku.
I... I...
I don't like this body.
Sengoku?
I don't!
Help me, Koyomi-oniichan.
I'm Karen!
I'm Tsukihi!
Hey! No matter how you say it, nothing is going to change.
Nothing's going to change!
Even so the guy who thought my name was Karen like in "Junjou Karen" matters a lot!
Yup, a lot!
One spells my name "Karen" but it's not said Karen, it's Kallen!
It's not Karen, it's Kallen!
He's not going to come back is he?
Is that what you think, Tsukihi-chan?
If you say it's not walking, that's it.
If so, that's it!
My name is like the "kuda" in Matsuo Basho's name.
What do you mean?
Atsukihi!
Like the Mogami River, you go to sea!
Don't dump me into the sea like that!
I don't know anyone like that.
Modern theme quiz!
Modern theme?
We're in the depression of the century!
Oh, she's serious!
Then, you'll hit the jackpot after 99 years!
What great luck!
Next time, Nadeko Snake, part 2!
Well, it could happen in less than a year.
Or it could also take longer than a hundred years.